I have to give a presentation tomorrow
and I am SO nervous
Yes, I can tell
especially when you stress the word “SO.”
What do you mean
I put emphasis on the word so?
How does it tell you how I feel?
When you put stress on a word
it means the word is important
You just said I am SO nervous.
That shows how nervous you are.
I can also put stress on different words
in that sentence, right?
Yes, you could say “I am so nervous.”
And “I am so NERVOUS.”
Each represents a different meaning
That’s very interesting
And how about “intonation”?
It sounds better when you have
the correct intonation, right?
Right. Usually a yes/no question
will have a rising intonation
“Do you have a new car?”
or “Is this his pen?”
But we usually have a falling intonation
in a statement sentence
such as “Nice to meet you.”
We also use falling intonation
in command sentences like, “Give me the key.”
and in WH-questions like, “What is your name?”
So when the intonation changes
the sentence has a different meaning
For example
a statement like, “You have a car.”
A falling intonation at the end of the sentence
means it’s a positive statement.
You can also have a rising intonation at the end
“You have a car?”
That might mean you don’t believe the person
you’re talking to actually has a car
So the intonation can express doubt
In a presentation, pronunciation is also
as important as stress and intonation, right?
Right. You have to remember that a presentation
is not just reading your notes
The audience has to feel you’re “talking” to them
The stress and intonation will help them understand
what you mean and what you want them to pay attention to
And how about rhythm?
Is that the tempo?
Because I am not singing
Hahaha. Rhythm is not only for music
You can speak fast or slow, soft or loud
Your voice can be high-pitched or low-pitched
Also, you need to pause from time to time
Together, these things make up a rhythm
If you don’t pay attention and speak in a monotone voice
your audience will fall asleep
Wow, that’s so important to know
I guess I’d better practice my rhythm,stress and intonation.
Yes, you should!